<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO8859-1" ?>
<ALL>
    <TEMPLATE>
        <NAME>Aneurysm ruptured</NAME>
        <TEXT>Bob Dylan
            Bob Dylan
            Bob Dylan
            Bob Dylan
        </TEXT>
    </TEMPLATE>
    <TEMPLATE>
        <NAME>Aneurysm unruptured</NAME>
        <TEXT>
Endovascular Repair of an Unruptured [location] Aneurysm by [procedure type]
 
Staff:
Assists:
Anesthesia:
 
Clinical History: [age] year-old [male/female] ([MRN]) admitted on [admission date] for elective repair of a [location] aneurysm. The patient [has/does not have] a history of previous SAH. [The last treatment was performed in [year] and the current procedure was [planned/unplanned]]. Informed consent for a diagnostic cerebral angiogram and aneurysm repair was obtained in the clinic. The patient was preloaded on [agents] for [days] days prior to the procedure. WFNS [...]. 
 
Technique:
The patient underwent general anesthesia and endotracheal intubation. Intravenous heparin was administered throughout the procedure after groin puncture. [Right/Left common femoral, Right/Left radial] artery access was obtained with a [size]-French sheath inserted by the Seldinger technique [under ultrasound guidance]. The [target artery] was selectively catheterized with a diagnostic Berenstein tip catheter through a [guiding catheter] and AP/lateral/3D-rotational angiograms acquired. This demonstrated an aneurysm of the [location] with a maximal diameter of [diameter in mm].
 
[Procedural description]

At the end of the procedure all catheters and the balloon were removed. [A 6 Fr | An 8 Fr] Angio-Seal Vascular Closure Device was used to achieve groin haemostasis. The patient woke up with no neurological deficits.
 
[There were no periprocedural complications. / The procedure was complicated by an intraprocedural aneurysmal rupture causing rebleeding which was managed with temporary balloon inflation for proximal control and coil closure of the rupture point. / The procedure was complicated by an intraprocedural thromboembolic event with visualized occlusion of [involved branch]. After awakening from anesthesia, the patient had attributable [weakness/numbness] in the corresponding distribution to the involved artery.]
 
Interpretation:
[Successful/Unsuccessful] endovascular [procedure type] for treatment of an unruptured [location] aneurysm. Modified Raymond Roy Class [1-3] result achieved. A follow up MRI/MRA in 6 months should be performed. 

        </TEXT>
    </TEMPLATE>

</ALL>