<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO8859-1"?>
<ALL>
	<SNIP>
		<NAME>
			Angio header
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TEXT>
			Staff: [...]
			Assists: [...]
			Anesthesia: [...]
		</TEXT>
	</SNIP>
	<SNIP>
		<NAME>
			Angiography technique
		</NAME>
		<TEXT>
			Informed consent was obtained from the patient (including risk of stroke and groin haemorrhage).10 ml of 1% lidocaine was infiltrated into the puncture site superficial tissues. A right common femoral artery puncture was performed under ultrasound guidance. A 5 Fr sheath was inserted. A 5 Fr Berenstein catheter was used to perform digital subtraction angiography. Injections were performed of the right vertebral artery, right internal carotid artery, right external carotid artery, left internal carotid artery, left external carotid artery, left vertebral artery. [3D flat panel tomographic angiography was performed via the ...]. A 6 Fr Angioseal was used to achieve groin haemostasis at the end of the procedure. There were no periprocedural complications. The study was reviewed on table by the attending staff.
		</TEXT>
	</SNIP>
	<SNIP>
		<NAME>
			Aneurysm description
		</NAME>
		<TEXT>
			Imaging demonstrates a [saccular | fusiform] [wide | narrow] necked aneurysm at the [...] measuring approximately [...].
			
			The aneurysm has [smooth walls | bleb | multiloculated] and points [...].
			
			[No branches arise from the aneurysm sac itself].
			
			There is an [Acom | PCOM | dominant vertebral artery]
			
			[MDT discussion is advised.]
		</TEXT>
	</SNIP>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			Aneurysm: Ruptured
		</NAME>
		<TYPE>
			Angiography
		</TYPE>
		<TITLE>
			Endovascular Repair of a Ruptured [location] Aneurysm by [procedure type]
		</TITLE>
		<TEXT>
			{{Angio header}}
			
			Clinical History: [age] year-old [male | female] ([MRN]) admitted on [date] for subarachnoid hemorrhage (SAH) secondary to a ruptured [location] aneurysm as seen on CT angiogram; Modified Fisher grade [0-4], WFNS grade [1-5]. The patient [has | does not have] a history of previous SAH [details]. An external ventricular drain was [not required | required and placed] pre-operatively. Informed consent for a diagnostic cerebral angiogram and aneurysm repair was obtained.
			
			
			Technique:
			The patient underwent general anesthesia and endotracheal intubation. [Right common femoral | Left common femoral | Bilateral groin | Right radial | Left radial ] artery access was obtained with a [size]-French sheath inserted by the Seldinger technique [under ultrasound guidance]. The [target artery] was selectively catheterized with a diagnostic Berenstein tip catheter through a [guiding catheter] and AP/lateral/3D-rotational angiograms acquired. This demonstrated an aneurysm of the [location] with a maximal diameter of [diameter in mm].
			
			[Procedural description]
			
			[There were no periprocedural complications. | The procedure was complicated by an intraprocedural aneurysmal rupture causing rebleeding which was managed with temporary balloon inflation for proximal control and coil closure of the rupture point. | The procedure was complicated by an intraprocedural thromboembolic event.] After awakening from anesthesia, the patient had attributable [weakness | numbness] in the corresponding distribution to the involved artery.
			
			At the end of the procedure all catheters and the balloon were removed. [A 6 French | An 8 French] Angio-Seal Vascular Closure Device was used to achieve groin haemostasis. The patient woke up with no neurological deficits.
			
			Interpretation:
			[Successful| Unsuccessful] endovascular [procedure type] for treatment of a ruptured [location] aneurysm. Modified Raymond Roy Class [1|2|3] result achieved. The patient will require an MRI/MRA during admission.
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			Aneurysm unruptured
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
			Endovascular Repair of an Unruptured [location] Aneurysm by [procedure type]
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Angiography
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			{{Angio header}}
			
			Clinical History: [age] year-old [male/female] ([MRN]) admitted on [admission date] for elective repair of a [location] aneurysm. The patient [has/does not have] a history of previous SAH. [The last treatment was performed in [year] and the current procedure was [planned/unplanned]]. Informed consent for a diagnostic cerebral angiogram and aneurysm repair was obtained in the clinic. The patient was preloaded on [agents] for [days] days prior to the procedure. WFNS [...].
			
			Technique:
			The patient underwent general anesthesia and endotracheal intubation. Intravenous heparin was administered throughout the procedure after groin puncture. [Right/Left common femoral, Right/Left radial] artery access was obtained with a [size]-French sheath inserted by the Seldinger technique [under ultrasound guidance]. The [target artery] was selectively catheterized with a diagnostic Berenstein tip catheter through a [guiding catheter] and AP/lateral/3D-rotational angiograms acquired. This demonstrated an aneurysm of the [location] with a maximal diameter of [diameter in mm].
			
			[Procedural description]
			
			At the end of the procedure all catheters and the balloon were removed. [A 6 Fr | An 8 Fr] Angio-Seal Vascular Closure Device was used to achieve groin haemostasis. The patient woke up with no neurological deficits.
			
			[There were no periprocedural complications. / The procedure was complicated by an intraprocedural aneurysmal rupture causing rebleeding which was managed with temporary balloon inflation for proximal control and coil closure of the rupture point. / The procedure was complicated by an intraprocedural thromboembolic event with visualized occlusion of [involved branch]. After awakening from anesthesia, the patient had attributable [weakness/numbness] in the corresponding distribution to the involved artery.]
			
			Interpretation:
			[Successful/Unsuccessful] endovascular [procedure type] for treatment of an unruptured [location] aneurysm. Modified Raymond Roy Class [1-3] result achieved. A follow up MRI/MRA in 6 months should be performed.
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			Cerebral Angiogram: Normal
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
			Cerebral Angiogram
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Angiography
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			{{Angio header}}
			
			TECHNIQUE:
			{{Angiography technique}}
			
			FINDINGS:
			
			Comparison is made with the ...
			
			[Normal cerebral vasculature is demonstrated. No aneurysms or other vascular abnormalities are identified. ]
			
			[A double read of the study will be requested.]
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			Cerebral Angiogram: Aneurysm
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
			Cerebral Angiogram
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Angiography
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			{{Angio header}}
			
			TECHNIQUE:
			{{Angiography technique}}
			
			FINDINGS:
			
			{{Aneurysm description}}
			
			INTERPRETATION:
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			Cerebral Angiogram: Dural Arteriovenous Fistula (DAVF)
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
			Cerebral Angiogram
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Angiography
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			{{Angio header}}
			
			TECHNIQUE:
			{{Angiography technique}}
			
			FINDINGS:
			
			Comparison is made with the ...
			
			There is a dural arteriovenous fistula centered on the  ...
			
			The dominant arterial feeders are ...
			
			Additional supply arises from ...
			
			Drainage is via ... in to the ...
			
			There [is/ is no] cortical venous reflux.
			
			Cognard classification:
			
			CONCLUSION:
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			Cerebral Angiogram: Arteriovenous Malformation (AVM)
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
			Cerebral Angiogram
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Angiography
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			{{Angio header}}
			
			TECHNIQUE:
			{{Angiography technique}}
			
			FINDINGS:
			There is arteriovenous malformation centred on the ... The nidus measures approximately ... in maximal measurement.
			
			The dominant arterial feeders are ... [en passage vs direct]
			
			Additional supply arises from ...
			
			[Flow aneurysms].
			
			[Number of nidal compartments]
			
			[Plexiform vs fistulous nidus]
			
			[Intra-nidal aneurysms].
			
			Drainage is via ... in to the ...
			
			[Venous ectasia or pouches]
			
			[Venous stenosis]
			
			[Brain parenchyma: venous congestion]
			
			Spetzler Martin:
			
			Size [] + Eloquence [] + Drainage [] =
			
			Supplementary:
			
			Age [] + Compactness [] + Bleeding [] =
			
			TOTAL =
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			Dural Fistula Embolization
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
			Endovascular Repair of Cerebral Dural Arteriovenous Fistula
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Angiography
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			{{Angio header}}
			
			Clinical History: [...] year-old male ([...]) admitted on [...] for elective repair of a dural arteriovenous fistula. The patient does not have a history of previous SAH.
			
			Informed consent for a diagnostic cerebral angiogram and fistula repair was obtained in the clinic. WFNS 1.
			
			Technique:
			
			The patient underwent general anesthesia and endotracheal intubation. Intravenous heparin was administered throughout the procedure after groin puncture. [...] common femoral artery access was obtained with a 6-French sheath inserted by the Seldinger technique under ultrasound guidance. A 5 Fr Berenstein catheter used to perform digital subtraction angiography.  Injections were performed of the right vertebral artery, right internal carotid artery, right external carotid artery, left internal carotid artery, left external carotid artery, left vertebral artery. [3D flat panel tomographic angiography was performed via the ...]. This demonstrated a Cognard 3 dural arteriovenous fistula fed by the left middle meningeal, ascending pharyngeal, and occipital arteries. The [...] external carotid artery was selectively catheterized with a diagnostic Berenstein tip catheter through a Benchmark guiding catheter.
			
			The petrosquamosal branch of the left middle meningeal was selectively catheterised using an Apollo (5 cm detachable tip) microcatheter, which was brought to the level of the fistula. [The same feeding artery was also catheterised with an SL-10 microcatheter, but it was not possible to bring the catheter distal enough to perform a "pressure cooker" technique.] Nevertheless, the catheter wedged in the vessel which most likely reduced the retrograde reflux of Onyx during injection. Onyx was then injected through through the Apollo microcatheter until the fistula was occluded. Final diagnostic angiography confirmed exclusion of the fistula with no distal thromboembolic complications.
			
			At the end of the procedure all catheters and the balloon were removed. A 6 Fr Angio-Seal Vascular Closure Device was used to achieve groin haemostasis. The patient woke up with no neurological deficits. There were no periprocedural complications.
			
			Interpretation:
			
			Successful endovascular treatment of an unruptured dural arteriovenous fistula aneurysm. A follow up cerebral angiogram MRI should be performed at 3 months.
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			Intracranial Atheroma Disease (ICAD) Treatment
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
			Intracranial Atheroma Disease (ICAD) Treatment
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Angiography
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			{{Angio header}}
			
			Clinical History: [age] year-old [male/female] ([MRN]) admitted on [admission date] for critical [...] [...] stenosis. [The patient was having ongoing hypoperfusion type strokes in the left hemisphere despite maximal medical therapy.] The patient was preloaded on [Aspirin and Clopidogrel] prior to the procedure.
			
			Technique:
			
			Consent was obtained from the patient and included risks of stroke (10%), reperfusion haemorrhage, and groin haemorrhage.
			
			The patient underwent general anesthesia and endotracheal intubation. Intravenous heparin was administered throughout the procedure after groin puncture. Diagnostic angiography was initially performed of the [...] with a diagnostic Berenstein tip catheter. The [...] ICA was selectively catheterized with a diagnostic Berenstein tip catheter through a [0.088" Neuronmax guiding] catheter and AP/lateral/3D-rotational angiograms acquired of the head and neck. This demonstrated [...].
			
			[A 115 cm Navien 0.058" intermediate catheter was advanced through the sheath in to the distal cervical ICA]. An [SL-10] microcatheter was then navigated across the stenotic level using a 300-cm Synchro Support wire. The microcatheter was removed and a [2.5 x 12 mm Trek-mini] balloon was used to angioplasty the stenosis up to a pressure of [4 ATM]. The balloon was then exchanged again for the microcatheter which was used to deploy a [3x21 mm Neuroform Atlas Stent]. Final angiography revealed improved perfusion of the left cerebral hemisphere.
			
			At the beginning of the procedure the patient's BP was approximately [190 systolic, and the blood pressure was 140 systolic at the end of the procedure]. [An angiogram was performed at this level which showed no evidence of early venous shunting to suggest hyperperfusion syndrome.]
			
			At the end of the procedure all catheters and the balloon were removed. An 8 Fr Angio-Seal Vascular Closure Device was used to achieve groin haemostasis. The patient woke up with no additional neurological deficits. There were no periprocedural complications.
			
			Interpretation:
			
			Successful endovascular angioplasty and stenting of [...]
			
			The case was discussed with the stroke team following the procedure and a maximal BP target of [140 mmHg systolic was recommended].
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			Carotid Stenting
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
			Endovascular Carotid Artery Stenting
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Angiography
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			{{Angio header}}
			
			Clinical History: [...] year-old [male | female] ([...]) with [...]ICA [stenosis | dissection. The patient was preloaded on [...] before the procedure.
			
			Technique:
			
			Intravenous heparin was administered throughout the procedure after groin puncture. Right common femoral artery access was obtained with an 8-French sheath inserted by the Seldinger technique under ultrasound guidance. Diagnostic angiography was initially performed of the [...] with a diagnostic Berenstein tip catheter. The [...] ICA was selectively catheterized with a diagnostic Berenstein tip catheter through a [8-French Flowgate Balloon | 0.088" Neuronmax guiding] catheter and AP/lateral/3D-rotational angiograms acquired of the head and neck. This demonstrated [...].
			
			[The balloon guiding catheter was inflated and under pump aspiration a | A] [0.014in x 300cm Synchro2 Support Guidewire] was used to pass the affected segment. Balloon angioplasty was performed with a [3.0mm x 15mm Trek RX Coronary Dilatation Catheter]. Good dilatation of the vessel was achieved. A [7x40mm Boston Scientific Carotid Wallstent] was then deployed over the affected segment. Final angiography revealed good vessel dilatation and no distal thromboembolic complications.
			
			At the end of the procedure all catheters and the balloon were removed. [A 6-French | 8-French] Angio-Seal Vascular Closure Device was used to achieve groin haemostasis. The patient woke up with no neurological deficits.
			
			Interpretation:
			
			Successful [...] carotid stenting and angioplasty. The patient should stay on dual antiplatelets unless instructed otherwise by the neurointerventional team. A CT/CTA should be performed within 24 hours.
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			Transverse Sinus Stenting
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
			Endovascular Stenting of Transverse Sinus
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Angiography
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			{{Angio header}}
			
			Clinical History: -year-old female (...) admitted on [...] for elective stenting of a [...] transverse sinus stenosis. The patient has a history of an occluded left transverse sinus secondary to a bony occipital tumour. Informed consent for a diagnostic cerebral angiogram and sinus stenting was obtained. The patient was preloaded on Aspirin and Ticagrelor for 5 days prior to the procedure.
			
			
			
			Technique:
			
			The patient underwent general anesthesia and endotracheal intubation. Right common femoral artery (5-French sheath) and right common femoral vein (6 French sheath) artery access was obtained by the Seldinger technique under ultrasound guidance. The left internal carotid artery was selectively catheterized with a diagnostic Berenstein tip catheter and AP/lateral angiograms acquired. This demonstrated occlusion of the left transverse sinus and stenosis of the right transverse sinus. The catheter was left in position during the rest of the procedure to acquire further angiograms.
			
			An 8 Fr Cerebase DA Guide Sheath was exchanged for the venous sheath and inserted in to the right internal jugular vein with a diagnostic Berenstein tip catheter. A 6 Fr Navien catheter was brought in to the transverse sinus over a Phenom 0.027" microcatheter and a series of pressure readings (mmH2O) were taken as follows:
			
			Superior sagittal sinus:
			
			Pre-stenotic transverse sinus:
			
			Post-stenotic transverse sinus:
			
			Sigmoid sinus:
			
			Internal jugular vein:
			
			The Cerebrase Guide was then brought in to the transverse sinus over an Advantage Guidewire and a 9x40mm Carotid Wallstent was deployed across the stenosis over a Synchro2 Support Guidewire.
			
			Repeat pressure readings  (mmH2O) were then taken:
			
			Superior sagittal sinus:
			
			Pre-stenotic transverse sinus:
			
			Post-stenotic transverse sinus:
			
			Sigmoid sinus:
			
			Internal jugular vein:
			
			At the end of the procedure all catheters and the balloon were removed. A 6 Fr Angio-Seal Vascular Closure Device and manual pressure was used to achieve groin haemostasis. The patient woke up with no neurological deficits. There were no periprocedural complications.
			
			Interpretation:
			
			Successful endovascular right transverse sinus stenting for stenosis. The patient should continue on Aspirin and Ticagrelor for 3 months. We will review in clinic in 6 months with a CT Venogram.
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			Epistaxis Treatment
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
			Cerebral Angiography and Epistaxis Embolisation
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Angiography
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			{{Angio header}}
			
			Procedure and findings:
			
			The risks were discussed with the patient, including stroke, vascular injury, contrast reaction, kidney injury, and groin complications. The patient was agreeable to proceed.
			
			The patient underwent conscious sedation. Right common femoral artery access was obtained with a 6-French sheath inserted by the Seldinger technique. Angiography was performed of the bilateral ICAs and ECAs with a 5-French Berenstein catheter.
			
			The diagnostic catheter was advanced in to the left ECA. A Prowler Select microcatheter was advanced into sphenopalatine artery distal to possible ECA-ICA anastomosis. This was then embolized under fluoroscopic control using PVA particles (150-250 microns). The control angiogram demonstrated decreased flow in the embolized territory. The same procedure was repeated on the contralateral side. The control angiogram demonstrated decreased flow of the target artery. No thromboembolic complications were observed.
			
			Following the procedure the catheters and the sheath were removed and a 6-French Angio-Seal was deployed at the arteriotomy site. Hemostasis was achieved and confirmed. There were no peri-procedural complications. The patient was transferred to the post anesthesia care unit in stable condition.
			
			Summary:
			
			Bilateral endovascular embolization of sphenopalatine arteries for epistaxis.
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			Middle Meningeal Artery Embolisation
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
			DIAGNOSTIC CEREBRAL ANGIOGRAM AND MMA EMBOLIZATION FOR SUBDURAL HAEMATOMA
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Angiography
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			{{Angio header}}
			
			Procedure and findings:
			
			The risks of the procedure were discussed with the patient and included that of stroke, vascular injury, contrast reaction, kidney injury, and groin haematoma. They were agreeable to proceed.
			
			The patient underwent [general anaesthesia | conscious sedation]. Right common femoral artery access was obtained with a 6-French sheath inserted by the Seldinger technique. Systemic heparinization was achieved. Angiography was performed of the [...] internal and external carotid artery using a 5 Fr Berenstein-tip catheter. A Benchmark guiding catheter was then advanced into the [...] ECA using over this catheter. An SL-10 microcatheter was positioned in the middle meningeal artery distal to the foramen spinosum. Catheterization and embolization was then performed of the [distal anterior and posterior] divisions using 150-250 Micron Contour PVA Embo particles. Care was taken not to introduce particles in to the lacrimal artery. A control angiogram demonstrated decreased flow/occlusion of these middle meningeal artery branches. No thromboembolic complications were observed.
			
			Following the procedure the catheters and the sheath were removed and a 6-French Angio-Seal was deployed at the arteriotomy site. Hemostasis was achieved. There were no peri-procedural complications. The patient was transferred to the post anesthesia care unit in a stable condition.
			
			Summary:
			
			Endovascular embolization of the [...] MMA using particles for treatment of a subdural hematoma.
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			CSF Venous Fistula Embolisation
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
			Embolization of Spinal CSF-venous fistula
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Angiography
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			{{Angio header}}			​
			
			TECHNIQUE AND FINDINGS: The rationale, risks, benefits and alternatives of endovascular treatment were discussed with the patient. It was also discussed that although this is a new procedure it is technically straightforward with a reasonable chance of success.
			
			​
			
			A right common femoral vein puncture was performed under ultrasound guidance. A 6-French sheath was inserted. A 5-French Cobra 2 Glidecath used to catheterize the Azygos vein. ​Digital subtraction venography revealed the Azygos system and the origins of the intercostal veins. Initially an Echelon-10 microcatheter was used to try and cannulate the right T10 intercostal vein origin but this was unsuccessful. Subsequently a 5 cm tip Apollo microcatheter was used to catheterise the relevant level which was then embolized with Onyx-18. ​​
			
			The vascular sheath was removed. 10 minutes of manual compression of the groin achieved haemostasis. There were no procedural complications.
			
			​
			
			Conclusion:​
			
			Successful endovascular transvenous embolization of a right T20 CSF-venous fistula.​
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			Stroke Thrombectomy
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
			Stroke Thrombectomy
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Angiography
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			Staff:
			
			Assists:
			
			Anesthesia protocol:
			
			
			Technique:
			
			Consent was obtained from the [relative | patient]. The rationale and risks of the procedure were discussed. The risks of the procedure included failure to recanalize vasculature, worsening of occlusion, intracranial hemorrhage, vascular dissection or tear, access site bleeding/complications, and the possibility of severe brain injury from the procedure.
			
			Angio suite arrival time: [...].
			
			Procedural start time: [...].
			
			Pre-procedural TICI: [...].
			
			The procedure was performed under [local anaesthetic with 10 ml 1% lidocaine to the right groin skin and conscious sedation | general anaesthesia]. [Right/Left common femoral, Right/Left radial] artery access was obtained with an [size]-French sheath inserted by the Seldinger technique [under ultrasound guidance]. The [artery] was selectively catheterized with a [Sim 2 | Berenstein tip catheter] through a [Flowgate 2 balloon | 0.088” Neuronmax | AXS INFINITY LS PLUS] guide catheter placed in the high cervical carotid. Digital subtraction angiography confirmed the proximal clot face at the level of [artery]. Extent of target occlusion in to: [...]. [There were no extracranial carotid tandem lesions | There was x% stenosis of the xxx]. [Multiple clots were identified on the baseline angiogram].
			
			PASS #1 ([start time] - [end time]): [To treat target occlusion at the level of xxx]. A [CAT 7 | ACE68 | AXS Vecta Aspiration Catheter ] aspiration catheter was brought to the clot face over a [Trevo Trak 21 | Rebar 18 | 3MAX] microcatheter and Synchro 2 guidewire. A [4mm x 41mm  | 6mm x 37mm]  Trevo NXT ProVue stentriever was positioned across the thrombus and deployed for 2-5 minutes. Target placement was achieved. Stent retrieval was performed with inflation and aspiration from the guide catheter and aspiration via the aspiration catheter started after stent retriever deployment. Technique used: [SR + Asp Cath + Pump + BGC]. IA lytics were not used. No device malfunction, distal/new territory embolisation, or adverse events occurred during this pass. eTICI after this pass [...]. [Use of angioplasty balloon, stent, other devices]. [Stenosis was not treated during this pass].
			
			8-Fr "Angioseal" to right groin puncture. There were no periprocedural complications.
			
			Summary:
			
			Endovascular recanalization of [...]. Initial TICI score: [...]. Final eTICI score: [...]. The procedure was discussed with the Stroke Neurology team. Plain CT is recommended at 24 hours or in the event of neurological deterioration.
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			Spinal Angiogram
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
			Spinal Angiogram
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Angiography
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			TECHNIQUE:
			
			Informed consent was obtained from the patient.10 ml of 1% lidocaine was infiltrated into the puncture site superficial tissues. A right common femoral artery puncture was performed under ultrasound guidance. A 5 Fr sheath was inserted. A 5 Fr Cobra C2 catheter used to perform digital subtraction angiography. Injections were performed of [...]. [3D flat panel tomographic angiography was performed via the ...]. A 6 Fr Angioseal was used to achieve groin haemostasis at the end of the procedure. There were no periprocedural complications.
			
			
			FINDINGS:
			
			Comparison is made with the ...
			
			
			INTERPRETATION:
			
			
			Dr J Lynch
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			Lumbar Puncture
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
			Lumbar puncture
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Angiography
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			Clinical information:
			
			Technique:
			
			Written consent included the risks of infection, bleeding, CSF leak, damage to nerve roots resulting in bladder/bowel incontinence and weakness. 10 ml of 1% lidocaine was infiltrated into the skin and subcutaneous tissues. A 22 Gauge spinal needle inserted into the thecal space at the [...] level.
			
			Opening pressure: [...] mmCSF.
			
			Closing pressure: [...] mmCSF.
			
			Samples taken and sent off to laboratory.
			
			No immediate complications.
			
			Requires 1-2 hours bed rest flat on back.
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			Nerve Root Injection
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
			Nerve Root Injection
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Angiography
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			**Procedure**:
			
			Target nerve root:
			
			Written consent obtained. Following  local anaesthesia a 25 G fine spinal needle was positioned coaxially adjacent to the [nerve root | Facet joint] under CT guidance. A mixture of 1 ml of 0.25% of Bupivacaine and 1.5 ml (3.3 mg/ml) of Dexamethasone was injected.
			
			There were no immediate complications.
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			Dynamic Myelography
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
			Dynamic Myelography
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Angiography
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			CLINICAL: [...]-year-old female with [...]
			
			COMPARISON STUDY:
			
			MRI of [...]
			
			TECHNICAL: The process of informed consent was completed with the patient. The patient was positioned with a single mattress and no bolsters in a right side down decubitus position markers were applied. With the benefit of local anesthetic a 22-gauge spinal needle was passed by direct posterior approach at the [...] level. Opening pressure was measured at [...] cm of H2O.
			
			Approximately 1 mL of Omnipaque 300 was injected to confirm the intradural position of the needle. Approximately 10 mL preservative-free normal saline was injected slowly over 3 minutes. The patient was then positioned in a head down position by approximately 5°, Subtraction myelography was performed with 12 mL of Omnipaque 300 chased with 5mL of normal saline. Imaging during the injection was performed in the AP view profiling the right lateral gutter of the thecal sac from the lower sacrum to the mid cervical region. [A second injection of 3cc of Omnipaque300 was performed with magnification over the lower thoracic region.]
			
			Following the myelogram the patient was transferred to CT in the right decubitus position and within 15 minutes of the myelogram CT was performed from C2-L3.
			
			FINDINGS:
			
			For the purposes of counting vertebral bodies it should be noted that this patient has 7 cervical segments, 12 thoracic segments each with ribs and 5 lumbar segments, the L5-S1 level demonstrates a small somewhat rudimentary disc.
			
			[A site of dynamic CSF leakage represent a complex appearing CSF-venous fistula was noted beneath the right T9 pedicle (a type III CSF leak). This was seen on DSM. ]
			
			No further areas of leakage were seen on this right decubitus myelogram within the cervical and thoracic region to the level of L3.The fistula was not localized on CT.
			
			SUMMARY:
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			CT Myelography
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
			CT Myelography
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Angiography
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			PROCEDURE:
			
			Written consent obtained. Local anaesthesia infiltration: 10 ml of 1% lidocaine. Under fluoroscopic guidance a spinal needle was inserted in to the CSF space at the L4/5 level. 12 ml of Omnipaque 240 was injected. After patient positioning maneuvers a CT was performed. There were no immediate complications.
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			Blank Report
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			FINDINGS:
			
			Comparison is made with the ...
			
			CONCLUSION:
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<SNIP>
		<NAME>
			CT Head Checklist
		</NAME>
		<TEXT>
			There is no acute cortical infarct, haemorrhage, or collection. No hyperdense vessel is present.
			
			
			[There is generalised cerebral involution with no lobar predilection. Bilateral hippocampal atrophy is present. There is periventricular and deep white matter hypodensity which is non-specific but may represent a mild burden of small vessel disease.]
			
			
			[Examine in 3 planes]
			
			[Blood: Sylvian fissures, prepontine, suprasellar, posterior horns, tentorium]
			
			[Cerebral swelling/cortical hypodensity]
			
			[Space occupying lesion]
			
			[Venous sinuses]
			
			[Basilar artery thrombus]
			
			[Contusions]
			
			[Collections: coronals for falcine (infective)]
			
			[Old strokes]
			
			[Atrophy | Hippocampi | Small vessel disease]
			
			[Clivus | Pituitary | Orbits | Cerebellar tonsils]
			
			[Paranasal sinuses | Mastoid air cells]
			
			[Extracranial soft tissue]
			
			[Shift of midline structures]
			
			[Skull: Fractures, lesions, skull base tumours]
			
			[There are no fractures or destructive bony lesions.]
		</TEXT>
	</SNIP>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			CT Brain: Acute
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			FINDINGS:
			
			Comparison is made with the ...
			
			{{CT Head Checklist}}
			
			CONCLUSION:
			
			[No acute intracranial pathology is identified.]
			
			[A neurology opinion should be obtained if there are neurological signs as further investigation may be necessary.]
			
			[If there is a high suspicion for intracranial haemorrhage lumbar puncture should be considered.]
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			CT Brain: Non-Acute
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			FINDINGS:
			
			Comparison is made with the ...
			
			
			[Lobar atrophy]
			
			[Hippocampal atrophy]
			
			[Midbrain | Pons | Cerebellar ]
			
			[White matter lesions, microbleeds]
			
			[Infarcts]
			
			{{CT Head Checklist}}
			
			CONCLUSION:
			
			[Normal intracranial appearances.]
			
			[A neurology opinion should be obtained if there are neurological signs as further investigation may be necessary.]
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			CT Head and Neck: Angiogram
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			CT HEAD FINDINGS:
			
			Comparison is made with ...
			
			There is no acute cortical infarct, haemorrhage, or collection. No hyperdense vessel is present.
			
			{{CT Head Checklist}}
			
			CTA FINDINGS:
			
			Comparison is made with ...
			
			There is no proximal intracranial occlusion or stenosis.
			
			[Collaterals]
			
			[Review aneurysms: Ophthalmic, MCA]
			
			[Vascular malformations]
			
			[Aortic arch and subclavian arteries]
			
			R CCA/ICA:
			
			L CCA/ICA:
			
			R VA:
			
			L VA:
			
			Basilar:
			
			[The extracranial carotid and vertebral arteries exhibit normal appearances.]
			
			[CT Perfusion]
			
			[Venous sinuses]
			
			[Cervical degenerative disease is evident. There is no acute fracture or destructive bony lesion. Dependent atelectasis is present at the imaged lung apices.]
			
			[There is no acute fracture or destructive bony lesion. The visualised lung apices are clear. ]
			
			[Pulmonary emboli | Orbits | Soft tissues]
			
			[Thyroid]
			
			CONCLUSION:
			
			No acute intracranial pathology is identified.
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			CT Head: Subarachnoid haemorrhage
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			FINDINGS:
			
			Comparison is made with the ...
			
			
			There is diffuse subarachnoid haemorrhage. The blood load is centered on *. There is also blood in the [basal cisterns | Sylvian fissures | convexity sulci | ventricles].
			
			
			There is hydrocephalus, with blood in the *.
			
			
			There is no acute cortical infarct.
			
			
			[There is generalised cerebral involution with no lobar predilection. There are multiple foci of hypodensity in the deep white matter in keeping with a mild burden of small vessel disease.]
			
			
			On the CTA, * [Refer to aneurysm description].
			
			[Second aneurysms: Ophthalmic, ACOM, PCOM, MCA, Basilar, dissecting, pericallosal]
			
			
			[There is no intracranial occlusion or stenosis.]
			
			[Vascular malformations]
			
			
			R CCA/ICA:
			
			L CCA/ICA:
			
			R VA:
			
			L VA:
			
			Basilar:
			
			[The extracranial carotid and vertebral arteries exhibit normal appearances.]
			
			[Contusions]
			
			[Old strokes]
			
			[Clivus | Pituitary | Orbits | Cerebellar tonsils]
			
			
			[Skull: Fractures, lesions, skull base]
			
			[Superficial tissue haematoma]
			
			[There are no fractures or destructive bony lesions.]
			
			
			CONCLUSION:
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			CT Head: Postoperative Deep Brain Stimulation (DBS)
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			FINDINGS:
			
			Comparison is made with the ...
			
			
			Bilateral transfrontal electrodes are in situ. There is no large postoperative haemorrhage, infarction, peri-electrode oedema, or evidence of other surgical complication.
			
			{{CT Head Checklist}}
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			CT Postoperative Subdural Evacuation
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			FINDINGS:
			
			Comparison is made with the previous CT of ...
			
			There has been interval partial evacuation of the subdural haematoma overlying the [...] cerebral hemisphere.  There has been marked reduction of the size of subdural haematoma associated with significant reduction of local mass effect and partial re-expansion of the cerebral sulci and ipsilateral lateral ventricle.  A small collection of blood products and fluid remains. There remains mild contralateral shift of midline structures.
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			CT Head: Haemorrhage
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			FINDINGS:
			
			Comparison is made with the CT of ...
			
			
			The large parenchymal haematoma centered on ... is again demonstrated. There is surrounding oedema. There is mass effect, with contralateral shift of midline structures and early transuncal herniation. Dilatation of the ... temporal horn is noted suggestive of early hydrocephalus.
			
			
			[A slender extra-axial haematoma is also noted overlying the left cerebral hemisphere. ]
			
			[There is no ventricular spill.]
			
			[There has been no rebleed since the earlier study. There is slightly more swelling and mass effect.]
			
			[There are no fractures or destructive bony lesions.]
			
			[Vein thrombosis]
			
			[Fluid levels]
			
			[Evidence of tumour]
			
			Surgical review is warranted.
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			CT Orbits: Cellulitis
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			There is fat stranding and enhancing tissue surrounding the right orbit. The globe is slightly proptosed. The enhancement extends in to the post-septal, predominently extra-conal, space along the medial wall of the right orbit, pushing the right medial rectus medially. Appearances are suspicious for phlegmon or subperiosteal abscess in this location.
			
			There is complete opacification of the right maxillary sinus, and almost complete opacification of the right ethmoid air cells. A small amount of dependent debris is present within the left maxillary and sphenoid sinus. These appearances suggest a sinus origin for the infection.
			
			No intracranial collections can be appreciated. The visualised intracranial sinuses opacify normally.
			
			Urgent ophthalmological assessment is recommended.
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			CT Brain: Neurodegenerative
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			FINDINGS:
			
			Comparison is made with the ...
			
			
			[Lobar atrophy]
			
			[Hippocampal atrophy]
			
			[Midbrain | Pons | Cerebellar ]
			
			[White matter lesions, microbleeds]
			
			[Infarcts]
			
			
			[Alzheimers: Early - hippocampus and the medial temporal lobe, Late - widespread atrophy. ]
			
			[Vascular dementia: Small vessel disease, lacunes, strategic infarcts. ]
			
			[Frontotemporal Lobar Degeneration (FTLD): Frontal and temporal lobes atrophy, may be asymmetric. Behavioural and language subtypes. Small caudate heads tend to be reduced in size in behavioural. ]
			
			[Cerebral Amyloid Angiopathy (CAA): Microhaemorrhages]
			
			[CADASIL: Confluent white matter hyperintensities in the frontal and especially anterior temporal lobes in combination with (lacunar) infarcts and microbleeds are seen on imaging.]
			
			[PSP: Concave upper border of midbrain (hummingbird)]
			
			[MSA-C: Cerebellar atrophy. Hot cross bun pontinehyperintensity.]
			
			[MSA-P: Low T2 dorsolateral putamen and lateral to putamen.]
			
			[Huntingtons: atrophy of caudate. ]
			
			
			[There is generalised cerebral involution with no specific pattern to suggest a specific neurogenerative process. Mild to moderate bilateral hippocampal atrophy is demonstrated. Mild patchy deep white matter hypoattenuation is apparent suggestive of a mild burden of small vessel disease. No large previous infarcts are evident.]
			
			[There is generalised cerebral involution with no lobar predilection.]
			
			[There is periventricular and deep white matter hypodensity which is non-specific but may represent a mild burden of small vessel disease.]
			
			
			Then a systemic search for these
			
			[Examine in 3 planes]
			
			[Blood: Sylvian fissures, prepontine, suprasellar, posterior horns, tentorium]
			
			[Cerebral swelling/cortical hypodensity]
			
			[Venous sinuses]
			
			[Basilar artery thrombus]
			
			[Contusions]
			
			[Collections: coronals for falcine (infective)]
			
			[Old strokes]
			
			[Atrophy | Hippocampi | Small vessel disease]
			
			[Clivus | Pituitary | Orbits | Cerebellar tonsils]
			
			[Paranasal sinuses | Mastoid air cells]
			
			[Extracranial soft tissue]
			
			[Shift of midline structures]
			
			
			[Skull: Fractures, lesions, skull base]
			
			[There are no fractures or destructive bony lesions.]
			
			
			CONCLUSION:
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			ASPECT Score
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			1 point is deducted from the initial score of 10 for every region involved:
			
			
			caudate
			
			putamen
			
			internal capsule
			
			insular cortex
			
			M1: "anterior MCA cortex," corresponding to frontal operculum
			
			M2: "MCA cortex lateral to insular ribbon" corresponding to anterior temporal lobe
			
			M3: "posterior MCA cortex" corresponding to posterior temporal lobe
			
			M4: "anterior MCA territory immediately superior to M1"
			
			M5: "lateral MCA territory immediately superior to M2"
			
			M6: "posterior MCA territory immediately superior to M3"
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			CT Cervical Spine
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			FINDINGS:
			
			Comparison is made with the ...
			
			
			Note is made of [an anterior cervical discectomy and fusion.]
			
			
			[The cervical spine is kyphotic.]
			
			There is ... mm of ... subluxation of ... on ...
			
			Disc space narrowing is noted at
			
			
			Neural foraminal narrowing due to uncovertebral osteophytes is noted on the right at ... and on the left at ... .
			
			There are marginal anterior vertebral body osteophytes from ...
			
			Multilevel facetal degeneration is evident most severe at.
			
			Atlantoaxial joint.
			Fusion
			Endplate change
			Uncovertebral osteophytes
			Marginal anterior vertebral body osteophytes
			Fractures
			
			
			[Vertebral body and disc height]
			
			[Skull base]
			
			[Posterior fossa]
			
			[Lymph nodes]
			
			[Scoliosis]
			
			[Thyroid]
			
			
			There are no destructive bony lesions.
			
			
			The imaged lung apices are clear.
			
			
			[Normal cervical spine alignment with preservation of vertebral body height and signal.  No spondylotic disc or facet joint changes.]
			
			
			CONCLUSION:
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			CT Lumbar Spine
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			FINDINGS:
			
			Comparison is made with ...
			
			[The examination extends from ... To ...]
			
			[Note is made of a transitional lumbosacral junction. The lowest level at which ... is designated ...]
			
			[There has been previous pedicle screw fixation and TLIF at ... No evidence of loosening or malalignment. There is a metallic cage is in situ.  ]
			
			[There is scoliosis which is convex to the ... at the ...]
			
			There is ... mm of ... subluxation of ... on ...
			
			A reduction in intervertebral disc space and endplate change is evident at ...
			
			Neural foraminal narrowing is present at ...
			
			Multilevel facetal degeneration is evident at ...
			
			]There are no destructive bony lesions. ]
			
			[No pars defects are present.]
			
			[Paraspinal masses]
			
			]The imaged lung bases are clear. ]
			
			
			CONCLUSION:
			
			[Pedicle screw fixation/metallic cage in situ with no evidence of loosening or malalignment]
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			CT Thoracic Spine
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			FINDINGS:
			
			Comparison is made with ...
			
			[There is scoliosis which is convex to the ... at the ...]
			
			A reduction in intervertebral disc space and endplate change is evident at ...
			
			]There are no destructive bony lesions. ]
			
			[Paraspinal masses]
			
			]The partially imaged lungs are clear. ]
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<SNIP>
		<NAME>
			MRI Head generic
		</NAME>
		<TEXT>
			[There is no acute infarct, haemorrhage, or collection.]
			[The major intracranial arteries and dural venous sinuses return normal signal flow void.]
			[There is no intracranial mass. The ventricles are not hydrocephalic. ]
			[Generalised involution is noted with no lobar predilection. There are multiple foci of abnormal signal in the cerebral deep white matter suggestive of a mild burden of small vessel disease.]
			[Blood: Sylvian fissures, prepontine, suprasellar, posterior horns, tentorium]
			[Microhaemorrhages]
			[Contusions]
			[Hydrocephalus]
			[Dural thickening | Leptomeningeal enhancement]
			[Intracranial pressure - optic nerve sheats, pituitary size, dural thickening, brainstem slumping]
			[Old strokes/lacunar infarcts]
			[Atrophy | Small vessel disease]
			[Clivus | Pituitary | Cavernous sinus | Orbits | Hippocampi | Cerebellar tonsils]
			[Sinuses]
			[Internal auditory canals for tumours]
			[Skull base -  look at DWI]
		</TEXT>
	</SNIP>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			MRI Head
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
			MRI Head
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			FINDINGS:
			Comparison is made with the ...
			{{MRI Head generic}}
			
			CONCLUSION:
			[No acute intracranial pathology is identified.]
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			MRI Head: Seizure
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
			MRI Head
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			FINDINGS:
			Comparison is made with the ...
			
			No mass lesion or hydrocephalus.
			
			No significant white matter lesions.
			
			No atrophy.
			
			No focal cortical abnormality.
			
			No malformation cortical development, vascular malformation or old damage.
			
			No temporal lobe abnormality hippocampal sclerosis].
			
			[The hippocampi are normal. Normal gyral pattern. No neuromigrational abnormalities are detected. ]
			
			[No localising or lateralising foci are identified.]
			
			[Medial temporal sclerosis: also look for 2ndry changes mammilary bodies, fornix, thalamus]
			
			[Rest of the temporal lobe/cerebral volume]
			
			[Tumour: DNET, ganglio]
			
			[Blood]
			
			[Cortical dysplasia: thickening, blurring]
			
			[Neuromigrational {polymicrogyria, heterotopic white matter}]
			
			[Encephaloceles: Anterior temporal lobe]
			
			[Hamartoma of tuber cinereum]
			
			{{MRI Head generic}}
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			MRI Head: Headache
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
			MRI Head
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			FINDINGS:
			Comparison is made with the ...
			
			[High IC pressure: Venous sinuses, Pit fossa - arachnoid herniation, Paranasal sinuses, Optic nerve abnormalities]
			[Low IC pressure: Sudural effusions, Dural enhancement, Midbrain descent]
			[Aneurysm, dissection]
			[Pit apoplexy]
			[SOL]
			[Colloid cyst]
			[Chiari]
			[Blood]
			[Paranasal sinus]
			[Craniocervical junction]
			{{MRI Head generic}}
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			MRI Head: Neurodegenerative
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
			MRI Head
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			FINDINGS:
			Comparison is made with the ...
			
			[Lobar atrophy]
			[Hippocampal atrophy]
			[Midbrain | Pons | Cerebellar ]
			[White matter lesions, microbleeds]
			[Infarcts]
			[Alzheimers: Early - hippocampus and the medial temporal lobe, Late - widespread atrophy. ]
			[Vascular dementia: Small vessel disease, lacunes, strategic infarcts. ]
			
			[Frontotemporal Lobar Degeneration (FTLD): Frontal and temporal lobes atrophy, may be asymmetric. Behavioural and language subtypes. Small caudate heads tend to be reduced in size in behavioural. ]
			
			[Cerebral Amyloid Angiopathy (CAA): Microhaemorrhages]
			
			[CADASIL: Confluent white matter hyperintensities in the frontal and especially anterior temporal lobes in combination with (lacunar) infarcts and microbleeds are seen on imaging.]
			
			[PSP: Concave upper border of midbrain (hummingbird)]
			
			[MSA-C: Cerebellar atrophy. Hot cross bun pontinehyperintensity.]
			
			[MSA-P: Low T2 dorsolateral putamen and lateral to putamen.]
			
			[Huntingtons: atrophy of caudate. ]
			
			{{MRI Head generic}}
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			MRI Head: Tumour Diagnosis
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			FINDINGS:
			
			Comparison is made with the [...]
			
			[There has been interval placement of a [...] ventricular catheter.]
			
			The [enhancing | non-enhancing] [intra- | extra-axial] lesion centred [...] is again visualised. It measures approximately [...] in diameter.
			
			[Ependymal enhancement]
			
			[Restricted diffusion]
			
			[Susceptibility -  bleeding or calcification]
			
			[Dural tail]
			
			[Bony reaction]
			
			[No prominent vessels or flow voids seen within the lesion.]
			
			[Bony expansion]
			
			[Centrally, the lesion appears necrotic.]
			
			[Dural invasion]
			
			[Words: Infiltrative | rarefaction
			
			The mass causes significant local mass effect with [shift of midline structures | subfalcine herniation].
			
			There is a margin of perilesional [vasogenic oedema | abnormal signal].
			
			[Evidence of raised intracranial pressure]
			
			[No contralateral or other space occupying lesions.]
			
			CONCLUSION:
			
			[High grade vs low grade]
			
			The appearances are most in keeping with [...]. The other differential to consider would be [...].
			
			[Referral to neurosurgery and the neuro-oncology MDT is recommended.]
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			MRI Sella: Tumour Diagnosis
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			There is an enhancing sella mass with suprasellar extension, elevating and compressing the optic chiasm. The sella floor has been remodelled and the lesion is most likely a pituitary macroadenoma.  There is no cavernous sinus invasion currently.  The posterior pituitary bright spot is present behind the superior aspect of the tumour.
			
			[Signal change and location (interface of the anterior and posterior lobes)]
			
			[Cavernous sinus extension]
			
			[Optic chiasm extension]
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			MRI Head: Tumour Follow-up
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			FINDINGS:
			
			Comparison is made with serial imaging dating back to [...] and most recently [...].
			
			There is no interval change in the overall size, morphology, or signal characteristics of the * centered on the * with extension into *.
			
			[Size compared to last scan]
			
			[Size compared to initial scan]
			
			[Signal characteristics]
			
			[Other neoplastic lesions]
			
			[No other brain parenchymal or extra-axial abnormality.]
			
			[There is no associated distortion or mass effect].
			
			CONCLUSION:
			
			[Stable imaging appearances.]
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			MRI Head: Postoperative Tumour
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			FINDINGS:
			
			Comparison is made with the ...
			
			
			Note is made of a ... There has been debulking of the tumour centred on ...Blood products and fluid occupy the resection bed. There is a slender extra-axial collection subjacent to the craniotomy containing gas and blood products. A small collection is also present in the superficial tissues. There is no acute cortical infarct or large haemorrhage. There is a small volume of pneumocephalus.
			
			
			There are residual enhancing margins predominantly at ...
			
			
			[The cavity causes mass effect, with mild contralateral shift of midline structures, which is similar to the preoperative appearances.]
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			MRI/MRA Head: Aneurysm Follow-up
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			FINDINGS:
			
			Comparison is made with the previous MRI/MRA from [...].
			
			
			The coiled [...] aneurysm remains excluded from the circulation. No other aneurysms are identified.
			
			
			[No sac enlargement or mass effect. No brain stem odema or hydrocephalus.]
			
			
			[The major intracranial arteries and dural venous sinuses return normal signal flow void.  ]
			
			[There is no intracranial mass. Hydrocephalus is not present. ]
			
			
			[Blood: Sylvian fissures, prepontine, suprasellar, posterior horns, tentorium]
			
			[Microhaemorrhages]
			
			[Contusions]
			
			[Hydrocephalus]
			
			[Intracranial pressure -  optic nerve sheath etc]
			
			[Old strokes]
			
			[Atrophy | Small vessel disease]
			
			[Clivus | Pituitary | Cavernous sinus | Orbits | Hippocampi | Cerebellar tonsils]
			
			[Sinuses]
			
			
			[Skull base -  look at diffusion]
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			MRI Head: Internal Auditory Meatus (IAM)
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			FINDINGS:
			
			
			Unremarkable appearances of the seventh and eighth nerve complexes bilaterally.
			
			The inner ear structures demonstrate normal appearances.
			
			No mass lesions are demonstrated within the cerebellopontine angles.
			
			No abnormal signal evident in the petrous temporal bones.  No diffusion restriction.
			
			Both trigeminal nerves are unremarkable. Meckel's caves appear clear.
			
			The brain is normal on the T2-weighted sequence.
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			MRI Brain and Spine: Multiple Sclerosis
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			SETUP: Compare the FLAIR initially.
			
			FINDINGS:
			
			Comparison is made with the ...
			
			
			[There is no interval change in the size, number or distribution of the white matter plaques seen in both cerebral hemispheres, corpus callosum and posterior fossa structures.
			
			[No features of recent or interval demyelination.]
			
			[There is a small focus of ...]
			
			[There is no pathological contrast enhancement.]
			
			[There are no infratentorial brain lesions.]
			
			[The optic nerves exhibit normal appearances.]
			
			[Optic atrophy -  nerves should be same colour as white matter]
			
			[No generalised or progressive cerebral white matter volume loss.]
			
			[No other intracranial abnormality.]
			
			
			[There is a plaque on the ... side of the spinal cord at ...]
			
			[No significant change in the number of white matter plaques throughout the spinal cord.  No significant central canal or exit foraminal narrowing.]
			
			
			[Normal cervical and thoracic spinal alignment with preservation of vertebral body height and signal.  No significant spondylotic disc or facet joint changes. No central canal narrowing.]
			
			
			CONCLUSION:
			
			[Stable lesion load.]
			
			[There is no evidence of progressive multifocal leukoencephalopathy.]
			
			[No progressive cerebral atrophy.]
			
			
			/*2016 MAGNIMS MRI criteria
			
			Dissemination in space (2 of 5)
			*   periventricular: ≥3 lesions
			*   cortical-juxtacortical: ≥1 lesions
			*   infratentorial: ≥1 lesions
			*   spinal cord: ≥1 lesions
			*   optic nerve: ≥1 lesions
			
			Dissemination in time (1 of 2)
			
			*   A new lesion when compared to a previous scan (irrespective of timing): T2 bright lesion and/or gadolinium-enhancing
			*   Presence of enhancing lesion and a non-enhancing T2 bright lesion on any one scan*/
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			MRI Brain and Spine
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			FINDINGS:
			
			Comparison is made with the ...
			
			There is no acute infarct, haemorrhage, or collection.
			
			[The major intracranial arteries and dural venous sinuses return normal signal flow void.  ]
			
			[There is no intracranial mass. Hydrocephalus is not present. ]
			
			[Generalised involution is noted with no lobar predilection. There are multiple foci of abnormal signal in the deep white matter in keeping with a mild burden of small vessel disease.]
			
			[Enhancement: leptomeningeal, cranial nerve]
			
			[Blood: Sylvian fissures, prepontine, suprasellar, posterior horns, tentorium]
			
			[Microhaemorrhages]
			
			[Contusions]
			
			[Hydrocephalus]
			
			[Intracranial pressure -  optic nerve sheath etc]
			
			[Old strokes]
			
			[Atrophy | Small vessel disease]
			
			[Clivus | Pituitary | Cavernous sinus | Orbits | Hippocampi | Cerebellar tonsils]
			
			[Sinuses]
			
			[Skull base -  look at DWI]
			
			
			[Normal cervical and thoracic spinal alignment with preservation of vertebral body height and signal.  No significant spondylotic disc or facet joint changes. No central canal narrowing.]
			
			CONCLUSION:
			
			[Stable lesion load.]
			
			[There is no evidence of progessive multifocal leukoencephalopathy.]
			
			[No progressive cerebral atrophy.]
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			MRI Spine: Fracture
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			FINDINGS:
			
			Comparison is made with ...
			
			
			Note is made of ...
			
			
			There is fracture of [...] involving [...] columns.
			
			
			[Posterior elements]
			
			[Retropulsion]
			
			[Spinal cord signal]
			
			[There is STIR hyperintensity in the [...] in keeping with fractures]
			
			[Ligaments]
			
			[Paraspinal soft tissue swelling]
			
			[Kyphosis]
			
			[Collections]
			
			[Facet subluxation/perching]
			
			
			CONCLUSION:
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			MRI Spine: Postoperative  Collection
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			FINDINGS:
			
			Comparison is made with ...
			
			Note is made of [posterior fixation involving ...].
			
			[Fractures]
			
			There is a subcutaneous collection at ... measuring approximately *. The collection has thick enhancing walls and is of * signal. It extends in to *. Surrounding tissue abnormal signal and enhancement is consistent with oedema.
			
			
			[Compressive spinal collections]
			
			[Enhancement of the bone/tissues/dura -  this may be postsurgical]
			
			[Spinal cord signal]
			
			[Epidural collections]
			
			
			CONCLUSION:
			
			
			Neurosurgical review is recommended.
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<SNIP>
		<NAME>
			Degenerative spine generic
		</NAME>
		<TEXT>
			[Fractures]
			[Vertebral height and alignment are maintained.]
			[Spondylolisthesis]
			[Scoliosis]
			[Bone marrow / Red marrow reconversion / Malignant infiltration]
			[Paraspinal muscles]
			[Vertebral body and disc height]
			[Collections]
			[Masses]
			[Ligaments]
			[Spinal cord signal]
			[Facet joints]
			[DAVF]
			[No abnormalities are demonstrated on the planning sequences.]
		</TEXT>
	</SNIP>
	<SNIP>
		<NAME>
			Cervical spine level
		</NAME>
		<TEXT>
			[Normal]
			[There is disc degeneration. | There is disc degeneration and height loss.]
			[There is a non-compressive disc bar. | There is a disc bar causing ...]
			[There is foraminal narrowing causing ...]
			[There is facetal degeneration.]
		</TEXT>
	</SNIP>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			MRI Cervical Spine
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			/*SETUP: 2 panes of vertical, with sag/axials up. Turn localisor on. Spine labelling.*/
			
			FINDINGS:
			Comparison is made with the ...
			Note is made of ...
			
			C1-C2:
			{{Cervical spine level}}
			C2-C3:
			{{Cervical spine level}}
			C3-C4:
			{{Cervical spine level}}
			C4-C5:
			{{Cervical spine level}}
			C5-C6:
			{{Cervical spine level}}
			C6-C7:
			{{Cervical spine level}}
			C7-T1:
			{{Cervical spine level}}
			
			[The cervical spine is kyphotic.]
			[Chiari]
			[Vertebral arteries]
			[Thyroid]
			
			{{Degenerative spine generic}}
			
			[Normal cervical spine alignment with preservation of vertebral body height and signal.  No spondylotic disc or facet joint changes.  No central canal, lateral recess or exit foraminal narrowing.  No intramedullary signal change seen in the cervical cord.]
			
			CONCLUSION:
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<SNIP>
		<NAME>
			Lumbar spine level
		</NAME>
		<TEXT>
			[Normal]
			[There is disc degeneration. | There is disc degeneration and height loss. ]
			[There is flaval thickening]
			[There is a disc ... ]
			[The disc contacts | The disc narrows | The disc displaces | impinges]
			[There is foraminal narrowing causing ...]
			[There is facetal degeneration.]
		</TEXT>
	</SNIP>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			MRI Lumbosacral Spine
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			/*2 panes of vertical, with sag/axial/sup.Turnlocalisor on.Spine labelling. */
			
			FINDINGS:
			
			Comparison is made with the ...
			[Note is made of ...]
			[There is normal formation and segmentation of the lumbosacral spine. | There is a transitional lumbosacral junction. I have assumed the lowest completely developed disc space is *. ]
			[The iliolumbar ligament is at L5. There is a fully formed S1-S2 disc.]
			
			T12-L1:
			{{Lumbar spine level}}
			L1-L2:
			{{Lumbar spine level}}
			L2-L3:
			{{Lumbar spine level}}
			L3-L4:
			{{Lumbar spine level}}
			L4-L5:
			{{Lumbar spine level}}
			L5-S1:
			{{Lumbar spine level}}
			
			[Annular fissure]
			[Pars defects]
			[Bottom of spine]
			[The bone marrow and imaged lower spinal cord return normal signal. No abnormalities are demonstrated on the localiser sequences.]
			{{Degenerative spine generic}}
			
			[Normal lumbar spine alignment with preservation of vertebral body height and signal.  No spondylotic disc or facet joint changes.  No central canal, lateral recess or exit foraminal narrowing.  No intramedullary signal change seen in the low cord.]
			
			CONCLUSION:
			
			/* Foraminal stenosis:
			
			[https://www.ajronline.org/doi/full/10.2214/AJR.09.2772](https://www.ajronline.org/doi/full/10.2214/AJR.09.2772)
			
			grade 1 (mild) refers to mild foraminal stenosis showing perineural fat obliteration in the two opposing directions, vertical or transverse;
			
			grade 2 (mod) refers to moderate foraminal stenosis showing perineural fat obliteration in the four directions without morphologic change, both vertical and transverse directions; and
			
			grade 3 (sev) refers to severe foraminal stenosis showing nerve root collapse or morphologic change. */
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			MRI Brain: Paediatric Developmental Delay
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			FINDINGS:
			
			There are no structural abnormalities, mass lesions, or vascular pathology.
			
			The gyral appearances are normal.
			
			No heterotopic parenchymal tissue is present.
			
			The corpus callosum is well formed.
			
			Posterior fossa contents are normal. There is no hindbrain herniation.
			
			The hippocampal, pituitary and parasellar areas are normal.
			
			The white matter is appropriately myelinated.
			
			
			CONCLUSION:
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			Radiograph: Nasogastric Tube
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			RADIOGRAPH FOR THE PURPOSE OF CONFIRMING NG TUBE PLACEMENT
			
			Technical note: AP erect film.
			
			Does the nasogastric tube bisect the carina (yes/no)? yes
			
			Does the tube project over the stomach (yes/no)? yes
			
			Approximate tip position:
			
			Other FINDINGS:
			
			PLEASE NOTE THE FINAL DECISION OF WHETHER IT IS SAFE TO COMMENCE FEEDING LIES WITH THE CLINICAL TEAM.
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			Chest Radiograph
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			FINDINGS:
			
			Comparison made with the study dated x. AP erect radiograph. The lungs and pleural spaces are clear. The cardiomediastinal appearances are normal. There is no free subdiaphragmatic gas.
			
			
			The abdominal appearances are normal.
			
			
			There are no destructive bony lesions.
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			Lumbar Spine Radiograph
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			FINDINGS:
			
			There is multilevel degenerative disease. Disc space narrowing is evident at [...] with consequent endplate change. There is facet disease, most florid at [...]. The visualised abdominal aorta is calcified.
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			Cervical Spine Radiograph: ACDF
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			FINDINGS:
			
			Comparison made with the radiograph of x. Anterior screw fixation and intervertebral cage at x is noted. The implants appear appropriately positioned and intact. No periprosthetic complications are demonstrated. Spinal alignment is maintained. The appearances are stable.
			
			Fusion
			Disc space narrowing
			Subluxation
			Endplate change
			Uncovertebral osteophytes  (posterior)
			Marginal anterior vertebral body osteophytes
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			Spine Radiograph: Postoperative Rod and Screw
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			FINDINGS:
			
			Comparison is made to the previous radiograph dated x. Instrumented posterior fusion surgery is seen involving the x vertebral segments with bilateral transpedicular screws and dorsal stabilisation rods in situ. An x intervertebral disc prosthetic device is present. The metalwork is intact. There is no fracture, periprostheticlucency, or other periprosthetic complication. The vertebral alignment is stable. Mild multilevel degenerative changes are again noted. Stable appearances of the remainder of the examination.
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
			Radiograph Series: Ventriculoperitoneal Shunt
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
			FINDINGS:
			
			Skull: A ventricular catheter is projected over the parietal bone with intact tubing descending vertically over the neck. The appearances of the skull and visualised cervical spine are normal.
			
			
			Chest: Intact tubing passes inferiorly projected over the right hemithorax. The cardiomediastinal contour is normal. It is difficult to follow the tubing as it passes over the level of the diaphragm.
			
			
			Abdomen: Intact tubing is seen with the tip projected over the epigastrium. Normal radiographic abdominal appearances.
			
			
			CONCLUSION: The tubing appears in continuity with the ventricular catheter and there is no kinking throughout its course.
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
	<TEMPLATE>
		<NAME>
		</NAME>
		<TITLE>
		</TITLE>
		<TYPE>
			Diagnostic Neuroradiology
		</TYPE>
		<TEXT>
		</TEXT>
	</TEMPLATE>
</ALL>
